Hello everyone, in this tutorial video, we will learn how to make a rabbit doll
First, we first create a circular board with a diameter of 300mm in the 2D window
Then we press the W key to click on the top of the board in the 3D window
Add a pin to prevent the board from falling to the ground after the simulation is turned on later
Then use the inner layer of the dragon layer to create a layer of the dragon layer
The dragon-shaped board will be automatically pasted near the original board
Here we choose the inner dragon layer, so the created board will be pasted to the inner part of the original board
But if you usually use a dense texture surface, then we can't distinguish right from wrong
After switching to the texture surface, you can see that the front of the board is white and the back is black
Now select this board on the back side
Right click
Then turn it over
So we can ensure that these two boards are facing out
Then we need to inflate these two boards, which is to add pressure
We add pressure to 10 here
Then press the control key to start the simulation
Then in order to get a better detail effect
We reduce the particle diameter of these two boards to 10
Start the simulation
After reducing the particle diameter, we will see that there are some wrinkles along the powder line
So we need to go to Fabric
To make some adjustments to the physical properties of the fabric in the fabric window
After selecting the fabric
In the property editor
Reduce the fineliner strength of the fabric and the tension of the foot line
The fineliner strength of the fineliner strength is used to control the stretching performance of the fabric
The smaller these numbers are, the better the stretching performance
Because now the fabric becomes very easy to stretch
So under the pressure
It will expand like a balloon
No wrinkles
The problem with the bottom of the board is that the stretching performance of the board is too good
The density is too high
After we reduce its density a little bit
It's like floating in 3D space
Because there are still some problems with the fixed needle
We can right-click in the 3D background and select the simulation property
Then go to the property editor
Set the force to 0
In this way, there is no force in the 3D environment
The whole board will float in 3D space
At this time, because there is no force
So when we drag the board
It will float in the position where we drag
Now that we have the ball body
We can start making other details
First of all, let's make this rabbit's face
Here we use the internal multidirectional line tool
Draw a inner line along the middle line of the board
Then select this inner line
Select cut and sew
Now the front piece is stepped into the left and right symmetrical half circle
Because the rabbit's face is left and right symmetrical
So now we use the adjustment board tool
Select these two boards and right click again
Select the symmetrical board, board and sewing line at the bottom of the movable board
In this way, after we modify one of these two boards
Another board will be modified at the same time
Then we will do the forehead part again
Just draw an inner line diagonally
Then select cut and sew
In the process of drawing lines
Press the control key to create a curve point
Double click to complete creation
After cutting and sewing
We can select this middle line of the forehead board
Right click and select merge
After merging, the forehead is a whole board
And the left and right are also linked
Then we are going to start adjusting the rabbit's face
Because the nose and mouth are relatively prominent structures
So we can use the editor board tool
Select this line of the mouth
Extend outwards to widen the rabbit's face
Then press the control key C to switch to the editor tool
Drag the neck line down
The curve of the chin
Let it form a meaty effect
Because the pressure has always been balanced
Now we have added some fabric
After modifying some boards
May cause pressure imbalance
Just press the W key again
Click here at the chin
Just fix the board
Here the rabbit's head is a bit crooked
We select all the boards with control A
Rotate with the positioning tool
Then freeze the rabbit's head behind
Although we just increased the rabbit's face board
But still
But maybe the amount of addition is not enough
Causing the nose position is not particularly prominent
Then we can appropriately
Extend the mouth line outwards a little more
Because in order to make the mouth and nose have a prominent effect
We increased the fabric
Causing the length of the forehead to match
So we need to adjust the forehead board
So that its length on both sides can match the face board
Now that we have adjusted it
You can see that the nose is a protruding structure
After adjusting
Move the board in the 2D window
So that they do not overlap
Then we can freeze the front forehead board
Let the rabbit's head be fixed in the 3D space
Then untangle the back headboard
Let it participate in the simulation
The front line is used here to fix the pin
You can also select it and delete it
Then we are going to start making the rabbit's body
For more intuitive confirmation
Wait for the position of the body board to be sewed
We can use the 3D board tool
Draw on the 3D board
Draw some reference lines on it
The sewing method is the same as sewing the inner line
Click and hold the Ctrl key to create a curve
Double click to complete the creation
To ensure that the rabbit is symmetrical left and right
We also cut the back piece along the middle line
After sewing
Apply symmetry
Now the symmetry is set
We can go back to the 3D window
Find the edit line 3D board tool
Then select the 3D line we created just now
In the right-click menu
Choose to convert to the inner shape
Because the panels are symmetrical
The inner line we created will also be automatically created on the other side
Because it is a 3D line that is directly converted
There are some extra inner lines
We can delete it
And we can select the inner line that has not been extended to the outer line of the panel
Extend to the outer line of the panel
Then we use the rectangular tool
Draw a rectangular panel that is about the width of this inner line
Click and hold the Ctrl key to change it to the inner line of the panel
Then click and hold the Ctrl key to change it to the line of the panel
Create the panel line
To maintain the current simulation form
We can freeze the top panel first
Click and hold the Ctrl key to start the simulation
After the simulation is complete
Go back to the 2D window
Select this panel
Press Ctrl D to create a symmetrical panel
Then we merge the front and the middle here together
Then select the front panel and copy it as the back panel
Then in the 3D window
Rearrange it and place it in the back panel
Rearrange it to the back panel
After placing it
Continue to use the line powder tool to sew the lines
Because the inner line on the back panel is relatively short
We also shrink the back panel
Finally we sew the sides together
To simulate the simulation effect
We need to select these new panels
Then modify their pressure
Because the bottom of the panel is now open
There is no balance
So our panels will fly around
So we need to use the line powder tool
Sew the bottom together
When sewing here
Pay attention to the direction of the line of powder
Now the body panel is like a small pillow
We need to use the circular curve tool
To draw a angle
We need to match the angle of the front and back panels as much as possible
Now this body panel may be a little short
And the bottom is not round enough
We can modify the panel shape
First, let's stretch the point of the waist out
To widen its waist
After modifying the front panel
Remember to modify the back panel at the same time
Then we can use the pen tool
To cut some curves on the side
Make it look more round and smooth
Next, let's adjust the length of the body
Because the width of the front and back panels is not the same
After applying pressure
The panel will fall back
We can adjust the panel
Press W and click
Add a pin
Fixed in the current position
Then we can choose the back panel to be frozen
Then we will start making it
To make the rabbit's feet
First, let's draw two internal circles
You can refer to the position in the 3D window
To adjust its size
Then we choose the front panel
Reduce its particle diameter to 10
So that the circle is smoother
Then measure the length of half of the ellipse
And draw a rectangular panel
Sew to the top
The width of this rectangular
Need to match the half of the circle
Its height
You can create it according to your needs
When using the sewing tool
To create a pair of多
When sewing
We need to select a whole section first
Then press the Shift key
To select the lines with only sewing
Finally loosen the Shift key
Complete the creation
Here we copy and paste a new panel
Then create the rest of these sewing lines
Then we need to create a foot panel
Here we can use the adjustment panel tool
After selecting the internal ellipse
To make it round
And then turn it into a panel
Then as before
We create a sewing line
It's the same
When one section and multiple sections
When sewing
Select one section first
Then press the Shift key
To select multiple sections
Then reduce these
The particle diameter of the newly created panels
To get a better simulation effect
After opening the simulation
We will see that the corners are a bit small
So we need to modify the foot panels
First, let's loosen the foot panels
After the selection
The center of the double machine selection frame
Can activate the center point
So that our loosening
It's all done by the center
After the loosening
We can modify the newly created
The pressure of these foot panels
Then we will start to modify the foot panels
Because the foot panel panel has just been loosened
So now we need to put it
This edge with it
Use to change the length
Then we will start to modify the foot panels
Because the foot panel panel
Has been loosened
Use to change the length
Change to the same length as it
Pay attention
Here we are choosing
When changing the direction of the length
You have to choose the two sides
That is, this option
After modifying the length of the bottom
Will lead to the corners of the side and bottom
It will be a sharp corner
So there are sharp corners
So we need to press the C key
Switch to the editor tool
To apply a curve to the bottom
The corner on this side
In fact, it is the corner of our bottom and side
Here we can also use
Editing curve point tool
To add some curve points
And by adjusting the position of these curve points
Let the bottom and side have a 90 degree angle
In order to make the middle section more smooth
We can add a few more curve points in the middle
To adjust
In short, we need to ensure that
The line section on the side and the bottom
It is a 90 degree angle between the corners
After modifying the bottom
We can also add a curve point at the top
Then adjust the curve
After this side is modified
We will modify the other side in the same way
Now the feet of the doll
The heel and toes are about the same length
When we are making dolls
Usually the heel will be a little shorter
The toes will be a little longer
So we move the bottom to the front
Move the level here
After adjustment
We can see that the heel part is shortened
The toes become longer
Watch the 2D version
We can see
After moving
The two corners of the heel are straight
But the foot in the front
That is, the foot of the toes
Still is the corner
Here we can add curve points to the side
And adjust the corner of the side to 90 degrees
Because we are modifying the side curve
It will also be reflected in the balance
Now the position of the toes
It looks round
Then select these panels just now
Press Ctrl D
Create a pair of symmetrical panels
Here if we want to make it
The shape of the toes
We can use the editor
Circle tool
That is, the shortcut C
To adjust the bottom circle
We can change these curves
To make it more obvious
You can see the shape of the toes
Then we start to make the arm
As before we add the body
Use the 3D line tool first
To draw the position of the arm seam
If you want to adjust the line we draw
We can choose here
Edit the 3D panel tool
Click and drag
Then it will be converted to the internal shape
After the internal line is created
We use a multidirectional tool
To create this curve just now
After creating a curve
Let's draw a picture
Like in the video
Then we merge the panels
To the body
After merging
Reduce the particle diameter
Because what we are making now
Is the part of the arm on the inside
So we need to
Turn the surface of this panel
Can be appropriately adjusted
The size of the panel
Then use the deep circle
Curve function to create the corners
In order to fix the arm
On the body
We need to use the fake sewing needle tool
After choosing the fake sewing tool
Click the hand panel
Then click the body
After opening the simulation
Just click these two points
Will be merged together
Then we copy and paste
A arm panel
Here for quick arrangement
We can do it in the 3D window
Copy and paste
Remember to turn the surface of the copied panel
Then use the hook and loop tool
Select the two lines that form a small semicircle
Right-click to select the hook as a panel
Then we put the hook out
The panel and the outer layer of the panel
Merged together
Then we put the arm panel
Then use the hook and loop tool
As before
Take out the panel behind the arm
Then merge them together
If the panel that is taken out
If it looks bumpy
Without flattening the entire curve line
It's because their particle diameter is too large
We need to reduce the particle diameter
That's it
Finally, we put the sewing line together
After the sewing line is created
We can put these panels together
Here we can use the edit sewing line tool
After selecting a set of sewing lines
Right-click to choose merge
You can merge along the sewing line
After the sewing is done
We can apply these two panels
Pressure
Because these two panels are facing out
So what we set here is the pressure of the stitch
And the pressure value is the same
Then press Ctrl D to create a symmetrical panel
And arrange them well
When creating a symmetrical panel
The sewing line will not be created in a symmetrical way
So we need to manually add the sewing line
Use the edit sewing tool
Click and drag the top of the sewing line
You can adjust the stitch
Because the stitch is based on the current angle
In the process of moving
If the current angle is not suitable
We can rotate to other angles
Then adjust
Now the body part is almost finished
We can add a four-leaf clover panel to it
Here we skip the production part of the four-leaf clover
Its production method is the same as that of the doll head
It is also to create a panel first
Then add pressure to the clover layer
Then use the free sewing tool
To sew the two ends of the four-leaf clover to the arm position
Now we freeze all the panels
Then start making the ear panel
For the ear panel
We draw such an ear pattern along the curve of the head
After drawing, we simply adjust the panel
Here, due to the bottom of the rabbit's ear
And the position of the body sewing
There is no breakpoint
We need to use the free sewing tool
Instead of the line sewing tool
Press the N key to switch to the free sewing tool
The machine points in the direction of the sewing line
Click the end point
Then press the Shift key
We are going to select the sewing line on the face
Pay attention to the direction
It is the same as the sewing line that selected the rabbit's ear before
Loosen the Shift key
After the creation is complete
We can start the simulation
Since there is no gravity in the 3D window now
We need to go back to the simulation property
Change the gravity back to 9800
To make the ear fall down normally
Then we press Ctrl D
Create a symmetrical panel
After the simulation is complete
We can reduce the particle diameter of the ear
After we select the rabbit's ear panel
Click on the application
Give them two applications of a new fabric
Here we increase the bending strength of the rabbit's ear panel
When the bending strength of the fabric is increased
The fabric will not bend easily
Therefore, in the position of natural folding
It looks thicker
Because we will set the thickness of the fabric later
So you need to press Alt E
Open the surface of the dense texture
If you feel that the position of the rabbit's folded ear is still too soft
If it's too thin
We can increase the bending strength again
Then we can adjust the position of the ear
After adjusting the ear
We can find the fabric of the ear panel
Then pull it down
Find its thickness
Increase its thickness
Now you can see that the rabbit's ear has been added thickness
We can use the depth and roundness curve tool
To make some roundness in the corner
Then select the twist tool
We can click on the panel in the 3D window
Create a twist
Then you can use the move twist tool
In the 3D or 2D window
To adjust the position of this twist
Switch the fabric window to button
That is, the twist window
Select this type of twist
Then in the attribute editor at the bottom
You can modify its shape
And its size
Here we can choose the twist shape according to the need
And adjust its size
You can also adjust its position again according to the need
After adjustment
We select this twist right button
Select the copy and paste version
After copying
We can see if there are any other places to be modified
For example, like now
This twist looks a little thin
We can adjust its thickness
Due to the twist in the default situation
There is a conflict
When you open the simulation
They will automatically float to the surface of the fabric
We turn off its conflict here
And set the length of the line as negative
So the twist cake will be hidden in the fabric
The tutorial video made by rabbit doll
It's almost over here
See you next time
Bye bye